<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/gpBlog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/gpBlog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-05T17:15:12+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gpBlog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Good Policies Blog</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cofounder Job Description</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gpBlog/job/ad/2019/09/27/Cofounder.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cofounder Job Description" /><published>2019-09-27T22:24:32+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-27T22:24:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gpBlog/job/ad/2019/09/27/Cofounder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gpBlog/job/ad/2019/09/27/Cofounder.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;co-founder-for-tobacco-control-charity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-founder for Tobacco Control Charity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-position&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The position&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am seeking out an altruistic and driven co-founder who is keen to maximise their counterfactual impact by starting high impact charities. I have decided to found a tobacco taxation charity, advocating low and middle-income countries (LMIC) to increase tobacco taxes. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/tobacco/mpower/raise_taxes/en/&quot;&gt;World Health Organization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copenhagenconsensus.com/publication/chronic-disease&quot;&gt;Copenhagen Consensus, state&lt;/a&gt; that this is the most cost-effective policy intervention that they are aware of in global health and you can read a summary of Charity Entrepreneurship’s research on tobacco taxation &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.charityentrepreneurship.com/blog/tobacco-taxation&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and GiveWell’s conversation notes where they discuss tobacco taxation &lt;a href=&quot;https://files.givewell.org/files/conversations/Yolonda_Richardson_12-12-17_(public).pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research and cost effectiveness analysis suggests that this is likely to be the most cost-effective policy to mitigate the disease burden from non-communicable diseases, which has been rigorously examined, but the organisation is amenable to other policies if a strong case can be made that they are likely to be more cost-effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsibilities&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work closely with the co-founder to shape the vision of the organisation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conduct strong research into effective public health advocacy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work with a co-founder to develop a strong strategy for M&amp;amp;E&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build the organisations network with public health experts and value-aligned funders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coordinate with existing advocacy groups and partners to ensure we are using the most effective strategies that we are aware of&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work with a co-founder to improve operations by building internal systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help to manage charity finances including budgeting and grant writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Passion: Deep enthusiasm about our opportunity to improve people’s lives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perseverance: Dedication to the long-term progress and sustainability of the charity and its intermediate hurdles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creative problem-solving: Ability to efficiently learn and execute best practices where they exist and to innovate where they don’t&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managerial and social skills: Ability to lead the team to meet project goals promptly, track progress, foster a positive work environment, and build professional partnerships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desirable-attributes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desirable Attributes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experience working in South Asia in global health or poverty alleviation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experience in advocacy roles in low and middle-income countries (connections to government would be particularly valuable)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to effectively grasp, critique, and present academic literature that will guide team decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to work out of London in the same office as the existing co-founder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desire to travel abroad when necessary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding of core Effective Altruism principles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experience managing sizeable budgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunity for highly impactful work whilst building career capital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High autonomy and creativity in shaping your role and the development of the charity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay according to your fit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexible work environment and schedule&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skill development in entrepreneurship, management, and institutional collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewarding team environment - this will be meaningful, interesting, and fun!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integration with the effective altruism community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working closely with a passionate co-founder deeply interested in these ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentoring and support from a network of experienced charity founders and executives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cause you believe in and a risk worth taking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;applying&quot;&gt;Applying&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your application should include two files: your resume and a document containing the following. Please complete this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/a97MRh1SffkjtGn88&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An evaluation of the above needs and wants that you meet (please be honest - good applicants will not meet all the criteria, but it will help to understand fit before interviews)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 short answer questions about the impact of advocacy (1-2 paragraphs each)
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make a strong argument for why advocacy based interventions might be amongst the most impactful&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make a strong argument for why advocacy based interventions might not be amongst the most impactful&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cover letter expressing what you would bring to the team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application deadline : 21/09/19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn more about who I am? &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/parikhcaleb/co-founder-info-slot&quot;&gt;Let’s chat&lt;/a&gt; or you can email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:parikcaleb@gmail.com&quot;&gt;parikcaleb@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; and to give you a sense of what I’ve done, you can view &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/caleb-parikh/&quot;&gt;my LinkedIn profile&lt;/a&gt;. I’m excited to pursue this opportunity and look forward to reading your application!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Co-founder for Tobacco Control Charity</summary></entry></feed>